No! Let me go!
不！放開我！
Calm down!
冷靜一點！
I don't mean you any harm. Please just calm down.
我不是來傷害妳的 求妳了，先冷靜下來
Aqua… how come?
阿奎亞…為什麼？
Mem said you went out in the typhoon,
MEM那傢伙說明明刮著颱風 妳卻跑出門了
but you wouldn't return, so she's looking around for you.
她一直等不到妳回去 所以到處在找妳
So I was following the route to the convenience store.
然後我沿著到便利商店的路線過來
You idiot.
妳這個笨蛋
Hey, you two!
喂，你們兩個！
That was dangerous earlier!
那樣很危險啊！
What are you guys doing?!
你們在幹什麼啊？
Akane Kurokawa's getting roasted.
黑川茜那邊炎上得好嚴重呢
Well, with that incident, it's no surprise.
不過，那樣的節目內容 變成這樣也是理所當然的
Don't you get used to this type of thing once you're a public figure?
這種狀況對於公眾人物 應該是家常便飯吧？
More or less.
或多或少吧
But it depends on the person, so some people never get used to it.
但每個人狀況不同 無法適應的人就會一直適應不了
Even for me,
就算是我
depending on my mental state, there are days when I think of actually dying too.
根據當天的心理狀態 也是會有真的想死的日子
The mind of a teenage girl receiving a storm of criticism for the first time
還是十幾歲的少女 第一次被指責謾罵集中轟炸
must be something unimaginable for you.
妳大概無法想像這種心境吧？
It's enough to make you believe that your life is over.
那可是足以讓人產生 “人生已經完了”的錯覺
Reality dating shows are popular in countries all over the world,
戀愛實境秀在世界各國都很受歡迎
but it's produced nearly 50 suicides up to now.
但至今也產生了將近50名自殺者
Depending on the country, counseling for the cast is mandatory by law.
有的國家法律還會規定 必須對出演者提供心理諮商
If 50 people are dead, then you should think there are ten times more than that
假設有50人死了 就代表有十倍以上的人
who have thought of committing suicide, but barely escaped death.
在自殺邊緣徘徊著 妳就這樣想像好了
Reality shows are a program where you expose your true self.
所謂的實境秀 就是暴露真實自我的節目
The one who gets slammed is yourself, not the show.
會遭到抨擊的也是自己，而不是節目
Of course that's tough.
那可是很難受的
My brother said, "Lies are also the best way to protect yourself."
哥哥也說過 “謊言是保護自己最大的武器”
That's well put.
說得真不錯
It's good if you created a persona to some degree,
如果在某種程度上扮演角色 可能會好一點
but the more you show your true self, the damage is deeper.
越是用真實的自己去面對 受的傷害也會越深
Social media makes the slander toward celebrities visible.
社群媒體讓針對名人的壞話清楚易見
By freedom of expression and in the name of justice,
在名為言論自由和正義的大旗下
someone is getting lynched every day somewhere.
每天幾乎都有人遭受著私刑
Everyone thinks of themselves as an exception,
每個人都覺得跟自己無關
but they are in fact cornering someone.
卻在切實地將別人逼上絕路
Your casual remark can kill people.
害死人的正是這樣不經意的言論啊
I wonder if Bro is okay.
不知道哥哥要不要緊
Even if you're careful, it's useless.
就算小心注意也沒用的
Like they say, "Everyone has their quirks."
俗話說：“金無足赤，人無完人”
Every person has some kind of flaw.
每個人或多或少都有小缺點
We all possess fuel to spark controversy.
我們一定都有會引發炎上的因素啦
Yes. That's correct.
喂？是的
What? Is that true?
什麼？真的嗎？
Yes. I'll be over right away.
好，我馬上過去
Is something wrong, CEO?
發生什麼事了，社長？
Aqua…
阿奎亞…
seems to be in trouble with the police right now.
好像惹上了麻煩，現在在警察局
What?!
-什麼？
My daughter told me not to watch the program,
我女兒叫我不要看節目
and I'm not familiar with the internet.
而且我也不熟網路
I never knew she was in such a situation.
沒想到是這種狀況
Why didn't you tell me?
為什麼不告訴我呢？
Because I didn't want to worry you!
因為我不想讓媽媽擔心啊！
When I was called, I prepared myself for the worst.
我被叫來時都想好最壞的情況了
But good job, Aqua. I'm proud of you.
但你做得很好喔，阿奎亞 我很為你驕傲
You look uninterested in others, but you're watching over people.
雖然你看起來對其他人沒興趣 但還是有好好關注別人呢
It's not like that.
倒也不是那樣
People can die easily.
人是會輕易死去的
If someone screams for help, you gotta move quickly or it'll be too late.
如果有人求救 就必須馬上行動，否則就會錯過時機
But I'll charge Akane for the taxi fare later.
之後我會向小茜收計程車費的
You're cheap.
小氣鬼
Akane!
小茜！
You idi…
妳這笨…
Why did you make us worry?
讓我們擔心死了
Why?! Why didn't you talk to us?!
為什麼？為什麼不告訴我們？
Sorry…
對不起…
Akane.
小茜
What do you wanna do from here?
妳接下來想怎麼做？
What do I wanna do?
怎麼做是指？
I'm saying you have an option to quit the show this way.
意思是就這樣退出節目也是一個選擇
But what about the contract and stuff?
但合約之類的怎麼辦？
This is an issue that questions the supervisory responsibility
現在已經是節目在未成年人管理方面
of the program that uses minors.
會不會被究責的問題了
Now that it's reached this point, they wouldn't complain if you wanted to quit.
既然變成這樣的狀況 妳想退出節目，他們也不會有意見吧
You're exposing your real name, Akane Kurokawa, on the show.
而且妳還是用黑川茜的本名在活動
You decide where to draw the line.
抽身的時機得由妳自己把握
I've been working hard all this time to become more famous as an actress
我是為了變成更有名的演員
and to continue acting.
為了能繼續表演而努力到今天
Everyone's helped me out so much too…
大家也幫了我很多
But it ended up like this.
可是結果卻變成這樣
Akane…
小茜…
I'm scared…
我好害怕
I'm really scared…
雖然我真的很害怕…
But I'm gonna continue.
但我要繼續
I don't wanna quit like this!
我不想就這樣放棄！
Alright.
我知道了
You heard her. There's no problems, right?
她這樣說了，你們沒問題吧？
Of course.
當然沒問題
That's what we've been saying from the start.
我一開始不就這樣說了
We'll try to back you up as much as possible too.
我們也會盡量配合的
You all get along on this set.
感覺真是融洽的片場呢
Well, this set's entire cast is around the same age.
嗯，畢竟這片場都是同年齡的人嘛
I'm sure everyone's going to work together
接下來大家大概會同心協力
and go through with the show despite what's being said.
就算有各種非議 也會將節目拍到最後吧？
But this leaves a bad aftertaste.
但就這樣結束真讓人不爽啊
The show that fueled the fire and those online who said whatever they wanted…
不管是火上加油的節目製作 還是在網路上肆意妄為的人
they all piss me off.
都實在讓人火大
PRESS CLUB
（記者俱樂部）
The police station has something called a press club.
在警察局有著 被稱為記者俱樂部的地方
Various media journalists stand by 24 hours to pick up the latest news
各個媒體為了獲得最新消息 會派記者在那裡24小時待命
and they're all waiting eagerly for a scoop.
即使是現在 他們也飢渴地在等候新的爆料
TEENAGE ACTRESS ATTEMPTS SUICIDE
（未成年女演員自殺未遂）
Now you've gone and done it…
你還真的做了啊
I was a fool for complimenting you.
我真是太傻了才會稱讚你
I hope you know where this is going.
你應該知道接下來的走向吧？
Yeah, although I don't know if it'll go well.
當然，雖然不知道能不能順利就是了
Now this is where the real reality show begins.
接下來上演的才是真正的實境秀
The news of Akane's suicide attempt spread,
小茜自殺未遂的新聞報導出來了
and it sparked various debates in the community.
並在社群上引起了各種議論
Of course there were those who backed off,
當然，雖然有就此住手的人
but new disputes and slander increased too.
但因為有新的火種，中傷也增加了
It gained attention, but there's no net positive outcome.
雖然獲得關注 但整體似乎也沒有好轉
This kind of thing just isn't a good countermeasure against backlash.
這樣可不能算是有效的炎上對策啊
In fact, Akane Kurokawa is still on hiatus right now,
實際上，節目拍攝時黑川茜仍然缺席
and she has no plans of returning yet.
她也沒有要回歸的打算
You selfish child.
你這妄為的孩子
Can you take responsibility for making this a big issue?
把事情鬧得這麼大 你負得起責任嗎？
I don't think this is a bad bet.
我倒覺得這是不錯的賭局
The amount of attention is the same as the poker chips on the table.
關注度就等於賭桌上的籌碼
If she folds now, Akane will lose big without having put up a fight.
如果放棄這場賭局 小茜會仍舊滿身傷痕，不戰而敗
You can't win if you don't raise.
就像賭牌不加碼就沒有贏面
I still bet even if I have only one ace.
就算只有一張A我也會賭下去
Real life is nothing like poker.
現實可不是賭牌啊
What? You want videos and pictures with everyone in it?
什麼？你想要大家合照的 影片和照片？
But I don't have that many. Maybe only 100 or less.
我可沒有那麼多喔 應該不超過一百張吧
You've got a ton.
這不是超多嗎？
What do you wanna use it for?
你要拿來做什麼？
Love For Real is content edited by a pro, right?
《現戀》是專業人士 剪輯過的內容，對吧？
So there's an intent there to make Akane the villain to make the show interesting.
這當中就存在 “把小茜變成反派會很有趣”的意圖
If you just cut out parts of a story and patch it together,
不管再怎麼樣的聖人君子 只要一味地斷章取義再經過拼湊
even a saint can look like a criminal.
也能將他形塑成惡人
That's what staging does.
這就是所謂的“節目效果”
I have the filmmaking skills, so if I just have the materials…
我有影片編輯的技能 只要我有素材的話…
I see.
原來如此
In other words, you want to make a Love For Real in our own perspective.
也就是說，你想要做出 我們視角所看到的《現戀》吧？
Whose advice was that? Did you think of it yourself?
這是誰的建議嗎？ 還是你自己想出來的？
Hm? I did.
嗯？自己想的啊
Really, that's not a bad idea.
嗯，不錯的想法嘛
This situation now in advertising agency terms is called
現在這種狀況 用廣告代理商的說法就是
"A situation with many active viewers where many impressions can be expected."
“有眾多活躍的受眾 就有更多曝光率”的狀況了
Akane's backlash stands out at first glance,
乍看之下攻擊小茜的言論很顯眼
but that's just the tip of the iceberg.
但那不過是表面而已
In reality, that's only a small percentage of the viewers.
實際上這樣的觀眾 也就佔幾個百分點而已
The sensitive topic of attempted suicide…
對於自殺未遂這種敏感話題
Most of the audience are wondering if they should support or criticize.
大部分的觀眾 還是會猶豫要維護或攻擊她
They're the silent majority.
也就是“沉默的多數”
In other words, many users are looking for an answer.
換句話說 還有很多的網友在尋求答案
That's where you provide a highly relatable opinion,
這時候如果提供一個 能引起高度共鳴的意見
then most people will believe that's what's correct in this market.
就會有許多人認為那是正確的 進而形成市場
We're the focus of attention right now,
畢竟現在這麼受關注
so we might be able to completely overwrite public opinion.
說不定能把大眾的看法完全覆蓋掉呢
And we have the access to upload your video to the official accounts too.
我們自己也可以 將你製作的影片上傳到官方帳號
The user flow is secured.
傳播管道已經確保了
Depending on the video's quality, we can expect it to go super viral.
根據影片的品質 說不定還能達到爆紅的程度
Once it's finished, gimme the data! I'll upload it!
完成後把檔案給我吧，我來上傳！
Well, I could do that much--
不用，那種事我自己就…
Do you know which day and time is best to upload to get the most retweets
阿奎知道星期幾的幾點上傳 能得到最多轉推嗎？
and how many characters in a post gives the highest impressions?
知道多少字的貼文 才能有最高的曝光率嗎？
No…
不知道
I came this far through online marketing and self-promoting, you know?
我可是靠著在網路行銷和自我推銷 才走到今天的喔
I may not look it, but I'm a pro at making content go viral.
別看我這樣 我可是炒作熱度的專家呢
Hm. Then I'll provide the music.
嗯，那我來提供音樂吧
You can do that?
你可以嗎？
Well, I am a pro who belongs to a record label, living off music.
我可是有唱片公司簽約 靠音樂吃飯的專業人士耶
I write the songs for my band and offer music to others too.
我有幫自己的樂團寫歌 也有為其他人提供音樂
I just gotta make some teary emotional songs, right?
只要弄點讓人傷感落淚的曲子 就好了吧？
Piece of cake!
這我最會了
Whoa.
哦
But you know, don't we want that one scene?
不過，果然還是想要那個畫面吧？
Which scene?
哪個畫面？
You know, the scene where Akane hit me and I kindly hugged her!
就是小茜不小心刮傷我 然後我溫柔抱她的那個畫面
Ah! Oh, but the camera wasn't rolling there--
啊！不過，那時候攝影機沒在拍吧？
Don't underestimate me.
太天真了
You think a pro model like me wouldn't take notice of the static camera position?
你覺得身為專業模特兒的我 會沒注意到定點攝影機的位置嗎？
I put us in a position that'd make us perfectly appear on camera.
我好歹也算是找了個 能拍出好畫面的位置喔
So much for a natural reaction…
讓人覺得有點白費感動就是了…
The staff definitely has the footage. They're hiding it on purpose!
節目組一定有那段錄影 是明知會這樣還故意不播出的
It's so unfair!
真是狡猾呢
Well, yeah, we do have it.
這個，有是有啦
But it's prohibited to carry out video data. I can't lend it to you.
但影片資料是嚴禁流出的 可不能就這樣給你啊
That's true.
的確
If that gets out,
畢竟放出來的話
it's like admitting the show set up a cast member to look like a villain.
就像是承認節目組 故意將出演者塑造成反派呢
If that happens while we're attracting this much attention,
要是在萬眾矚目的這個時候被公開
Akane's bashing may shift towards the show.
對小茜的攻擊可能就會轉向節目組呢
You catch on quick.
你理解得很快真是太好了
What we're doing is a form of entertainment known as a reality show.
我們製作的是名為實境秀的娛樂節目
Everyone watches the show looking forward to the real drama.
觀眾都是期待看到真實的糾紛 才來看節目的
We don't force anything onto Akane.
我們沒有強迫小茜做任何事
She makes the decisions,
那是她自己的選擇
and we're just staging it so that the audience easily understands.
我們只是剪輯得 讓觀眾更容易理解而已
If she refused the job, we wouldn't have used her either.
她要是不樂意 只要說出哪段不行，我們就不會播出
Am I wrong?
不是嗎？
Akane has a highly responsible personality.
小茜是責任感很強的人喔
I know, I've been filming her.
我知道，我一直在拍嘛
Akane is a pro, but we're also doing this as a profession.
小茜是專業人士 我們也只是在做自己的工作
A pro, huh…
專業人士啊…
Director, how old are you?
導演您現在幾歲？
I'm 35.
35歲
Akane's 17.
小茜才17歲
Whether she's a pro or not,
先不論她是不是專業人士
a 17-year-old is just a damn brat who makes a bunch of mistakes.
17歲的小屁孩會犯一堆錯 也是理所當然的吧？
If the grown-ups won't protect the kids, then who will?
身為大人卻不保護孩子 說得過去嗎？
You got a point there.
真會說啊
Ugh, no, no!
啊，不對！
Make that shot long, so it'll look more like an amateur worked on it!
這裡要用長鏡頭 才能表現出像是業餘努力的感覺
This is where you add my song!
這裡要加入我的曲子吧！
Make it go "Bang!"
就做成“碰”的感覺吧！
Shut up…
吵死了
The staff gave me this photo!
工作人員還給了我這種照片！
Awesome! Let's use it!
天啊！用吧！
Um, the composition…
不是，那影片結構…
Nice!
不錯耶！
Looks real nice!
非常不錯！
Come on, Director, it finished encoding. We're gonna post it.
導演，編碼完成了，我要發貼文了喔
Damn it, that computer has some good specs.
可惡，妳的電腦配備也太好了吧
Let me sleep more…
我還想多睡一下啊
I wonder how many views it'll get.
不知道會有多少觀看數呢？
I hope it hits at least 5,000.
希望至少能有五千次呢
Even that's pretty hard.
那也還是蠻難的喔
The videos you put more effort into don't take off as expected sometimes.
越是努力做出來的影片 就越是意外地不如預期呢
If we can get 100 retweets in the first minute,
在一開始的一分鐘內 能有一百次轉推的話
it should ultimately become a pretty viral video.
應該最後就會有不得了的熱度吧
A hundred?
一百次嗎？
Well, we did all that we could. Now, let's go for the showdown!
嗯，畢竟已經盡力了 現在是決勝的時刻了！
You haven't done anything though.
你明明什麼都沒做
Why are you acting like the leader?
還擺出一副領袖的樣子也太那個了
VIEWS 0
（觀看次數0次）
VIEWS 50 3 RETWEETS
（觀看次數50次，3則轉推）
VIEWS 257 6 RETWEETS
（觀看次數257次，6則轉推）
VIEWS 1,282 58 RETWEETS
（觀看次數1282次 58則轉推）
VIEWS 2,546 92 RETWEETS
（觀看次數2546次 92則轉推）
This'll work! This'll go viral! Here it comes!
成功了，這樣可以！來吧！
VIEWS 8,576 226 RETWEETS
（觀看次數8576次 226則轉推）
Alright!
-好耶！
I understand, you just panicked.
我明白，妳只是有點急躁，對吧？
Sorry… Your face… And you have a magazine shoot…
對不起，妳的臉… 明明還有雜誌拍攝…
Don't worry.
沒關係
Akane, do you hate me?
小茜，妳討厭我嗎？
I don't hate you.
不討厭
You're strong and kind, I like you.
妳又堅強又溫柔，我很喜歡呢
Me too. I like you and your hardworking, earnest self.
我也是喔，我也很喜歡 努力不懈、凡事竭盡全力的小茜
That's why I won't get mad.
所以我才不會生氣呢
This video received 74,000 retweets 24 hours later.
這部影片在24小時後 獲得74,000次轉推
It revamped Akane Kurokawa's image,
在反轉了黑川茜的形象的同時
as well as established Love For Real's popularity at the same time.
也成為了決定《現戀》人氣的轉折點
THE CAST IS CLOSE…
（成員的關係真好…）
YUKI DOESN'T WANT BASHING…
（夕雪大概也不想要小茜被圍攻吧）
IT'S TRENDY TO SLAM THE SHOW NOW? LOL
（這什麼？要攻擊節目組嗎？ 你們叛變得太快了吧）
ALL AT ONCE TOO
（牆頭草可真忙啊）
The backlash had settled to some degree.
炎上騷動在某種程度上平息了
Why I word that vaguely is because
說得這麼模稜兩可是因為
there is no complete solution to backlash.
炎上是不可能完全解決的
Akane!
小茜！
I'm sure this matter will continue to be brought up again,
今後要是有什麼契機 這件事還是會被提起
and even a decade later, there will be those who mention it.
會繼續謾罵的人 即使再過十年，也還是會繼續下去
But… Yeah, I'll return starting the next shoot.
不過呢，對 我會在下次拍攝時回來的
I'm so glad!
太好了！
But don't push yourself to go on the show.
但是不用勉強自己參加喔
Uh, that wasn't meant in a bad way, okay?
啊，那句不是不要妳來的意思喔！
Since I want you to go on the show even if you pushed yourself!
對我來說 是希望妳有點勉強也要來參加的
I know.
我知道
I feel that it's become a difficult world to voice your opinion.
現在這世道真是越來越難說話了
I bet I would've gotten backlash for it if I tweeted that now.
剛剛要是發到推特上 肯定會小燒一波吧
I seriously gotta be careful.
真的得小心點才行
From now on, maybe you should create a bit of a persona?
以後小茜也塑造個角色比較好吧？
If you show your true self, it'll hit you harder if you get slammed.
畢竟如果展現赤裸裸的自己 被攻擊時就很容易重傷呢
A persona?
角色？
That's true…
沒錯
If you act out some kind of role, that'll become your armor.
扮演某個角色時 那個角色就會化為盔甲
If you expose your true self, you just get hurt.
展現真正的自己只會受傷罷了
This isn't exactly limited to reality shows either.
這不是只限於實境秀
It's a vital concept in socializing too.
在社交技術上也是很重要的概念
Since Aqua's a man of many faces too, so…
阿奎也扮演了好多角色呢
You can show us more of yourself, you know?
在我們面前多多展現自己 也是可以的喔
I refuse.
我拒絕
I'm good at acting, so maybe I'll try it.
我還蠻擅長演戲的，要不要試試呢？
That's right, you are an actress after all, Akane.
對喔，畢竟小茜是演員嘛
Rather, that's the only strength I have…
不如說除此之外沒有長處了…
But what kind of role should I act out?
但我要演什麼樣的角色好呢？
Hmm.
嗯…
Aqua, what kind of girl is your type?
阿奎喜歡什麼樣的女孩子？
Why me?
為什麼問我啊？
Because you're the only guy here.
因為現在只有你一個男生啊
Tell her what your ideal girl is like.
告訴我們你理想的女生類型嘛
Ideal…
理想…
A girl with a pretty face.
長得漂亮的女生
Ugh, that's the worst.
嗚哇，有夠差勁
You are the epitome of lookism.
出現了，外貌至上主義的化身
With a bright smile like sunshine.
有著太陽一般的笑容
A perfect performance.
完美的表演能力
An invincible manner and speech.
簡直所向無敵的言行
Huh?
啊？
Natural captivating eyes.
充滿靈性、令人深陷的雙眼
You say some difficult stuff.
你說得還真難懂
That's vague…
很抽象呢
Hmm, but maybe it's like her?
嗯，但怎麼說呢？
Maybe like B Komachi's Ai?
像是B小町的愛一樣？
Ai as in the idol who died a long time ago?
愛是好久以前去世的那個偶像嗎？
Uh-huh.
對
Am I wrong?
不對嗎？
Uh, well, that's about right.
嗯，大致上符合吧
Ah, so you like these types!
啊，原來喜歡這種類型啊
You're a sucker for pretty faces!
真是外貌控呢
I'll try acting out Aqua's type of girl then.
那我就試著扮演 阿奎亞喜歡的女孩子吧
Do it!
上吧！
Make Aqua fall for you!
攻陷阿奎亞的心！
Yeah!
耶！
No one can copy Ai. She's a natural-born star.
沒有人可以模仿愛的 那是與生俱來的靈性
I'll do my best.
我得加油
Aqua worked hard to make that video for me.
阿奎亞為了我拼命製作影片
He also came to find me in a storm.
還冒著颱風出來找我
That made me happy.
我好開心
I need to repay him.
得報答他這份恩情才行
I wonder if he'll be happy if I act out his type and showed him.
如果能扮演好他喜歡的類型 不曉得他會不會開心呢？
B Komachi's Ai… I need to gather data.
B小町的愛…要收集資料才行
Her main trait must be those eyes.
最大的特徵果然還是眼神
Did it come from self-confidence?
是來自於自信嗎？
NATURAL CAPTIVATING EYES
（生來令人深陷的雙眼）
If so, that means her desire for recognition was being satisfied.
如果是這樣 代表她的認同需求是有得到滿足的
Her social life seems limited.
交友關係很有限呢
But I'm sure there was something with the opposite sex…
那應該是有一定程度的異性關係吧
Was her home environment good?
家庭環境很好嗎？
No, this personality probably developed from a very bad one.
不對，這種人格的形成 可能家境偏向惡劣
It seems she had some type of bias towards the way she loved others.
表現愛的方式似乎有種偏頗
Secretive but desired exposure.
祕密主義但有暴露欲
A perfectionist despite being reckless.
與大剌剌的言行相反的完美主義者
Careless but overly persistent.
缺乏關心但又過度執著
The type to save money.
金錢觀念偏向節制
Rather disinterested in fashion.
對時尚不怎麼關注
Good vision.
視力很好
Sensitive ears and nose.
聽覺和嗅覺異常敏銳
Long steps when walking.
走路喜歡大步走
Relatively poorly educated.
教育程度偏低
A crooked way of holding chopsticks.
拿筷子的姿勢不標準
Signs of developmental disorder.
有發展障礙的跡象
An unbalance seen in girls who've had intercourse at the adolescent stage.
具有女孩子在青春期 有過性經驗的不平衡感
From around 15 years old, you can see an improvement in her reckless behavior.
在15歲左右 自我毀滅的舉止有了改善
I wonder if she met someone nice?
有了一場美好的邂逅嗎？
ICHIGO PRODUCTION SAITOU
（草莓娛樂製作有限公司，齊藤）
Akane Kurokawa went through a disaster. Does she seem okay?
黑川茜那邊很不容易吧，還好嗎？
Yeah, she recovered somehow.
嗯，姑且是好轉了吧
I see.
這樣啊
Aww, I wish she had just retired.
唉，要是她就這樣引退就好了呢
Hey…
妳啊…
Oh! No, no, that's not what I meant!
啊！不是，我不是那個意思！
As a business rival!
是作為事業對手來說啦
Ugh, a bad choice of words can be scary. That would've blown up if I tweeted that.
唉，語言真可怕 剛剛的話發到推特，肯定會被燒的
Even as a business rival, that doesn't make it sound any better.
就算是事業對手 也不能成為口出惡言的藉口喔
Well, as someone who's the same age with the same job as an actress…
不是啦，是作為同年齡 又同樣是演員的人來說
she's like an eyesore.
她的存在就像眼中釘
You can understand when you want your rival to fall, right?
會希望她偶爾失敗一下 也是可以理解的吧？
It's basically Schadenfreude.
就是所謂的幸災樂禍啦
Kana Arima feels that way toward Akane Kurokawa?
有馬佳奈對黑川茜幸災樂禍？
Well of course.
那是當然的啊
Right. You had no interest in theater.
對喔，你對戲劇圈沒興趣呢
Well, you only act in front of a camera.
畢竟你只有在攝影機前演戲
Akane Kurokawa of Theater Lalalai
說到拉拉萊劇團的黑川茜
is famous in the theater world for being a genius actress.
在業界可是很有名的天才演員喔
Akane will return starting today.
今天起小茜回歸拍攝了
Everyone, I apologize for causing so much trouble.
給大家造成麻煩真的非常抱歉
I'd like to make up for it with my efforts from here.
希望能用我的努力來彌補過失
I kindly ask for your cooperation!
請大家多多關照！
Now then, please stand by for the camera.
那麼，準備開始拍攝了喔
Let's go.
走吧
Yeah.
嗯
Sure, Aqua.
好的，阿奎亞
I'm so sleepy! This shoot is too early.
好想睡喔，拍攝時間也太早了吧
Oh, is the camera rolling already?
啊，已經開始在拍了嗎？
Tee-hee!
欸嘿！
Subtitle translation by: Kanami Kitabayashi
字幕翻譯：楊易